[Music]
hey welcome back uh so today is day
two of the tinkercad class uh i'm here
with uh with my student again
uh so this is uh mckinley you ready to
go today mckinley yep
all right we're gonna do some uh some
circuits today so
tinkercad um is built with
uh 3d model support so it's kind of what
we did yesterday with the rocket in the
house
it's built with circuits so you can do
things with like simulating circuits and
that's what we're going to do
today tomorrow and thursday and then
it's also got this new thing called code
blocks we'll do that on friday
so today we're going to go with circuits
i'm going to show you the solutions to
some things we're going to build
so we're going to build a pretty complex
program
just teasing that has an led so we're
going to show you the right way
to hook up an led with the resistor so
that you can turn it on and off
with this button um and that'll make the
led go on and off and then the wrong way
to do it
uh without a resistor and their little
simulator shows
disaster right so it explodes on you
right uh so that's one thing we're going
to build today another thing we're going
to build today
this is the main project is a stoplight
simulator
so i'm going to click on start simulator
here and so we're going to write code
for the stop cycle light simulator
and we're also going to build it in a
simulated environment
such that if you hit this push button so
i push this button button
my stop light goes green and then yellow
and then red
it goes pretty quickly just because it
makes the simulation work better
now the fun thing about what we're going
to learn today is these skills are
things that you could transfer to uh to
real products right
so i've got an arduino uno here
this one is part of a kit that comes
from sparkfun it's a pretty good kit
it's their sparkfun inventor kit
but i've actually taken the code that
we're going to write together and
put it on this real board and you can
see that when i push the button
it does the same thing on a real board
so everything that we're doing
in the simulator here is something that
if you happen to have the actual
hardware
you could totally build right so for
people that happen to have an arduino
sitting in a closet somewhere
uh they could do that by the way if you
did want to buy
an arduino you could look on amazon
there's some great kits out there
e lagoo has some cheap ones the spark
phone was also awesome it's just a
little more expensive
uh so let's go ahead and get started so
uh log in to
tinkercad uh hopefully you know how to
do that at this point
um and instead of being in the 3d design
area go into the circuits area
now when you come into circuits there
should be a
try circuits like tutorial here that you
can get started on
let's go ahead and go through that
tutorial it's only like three or four
parts this time so it's much shorter
if you don't have that tutorial you
could always get there via the learn
approach and like you could get there
but it should just be sitting right here
which is great i wish they did that for
the three designs i don't know what they
did they didn't
i would go and click on try circuits and
what it's going to do is it's going to
introduce us
to using circuits in a very brief
tutorial
so this is their first tutorial it's
very short it brings up a battery
this one is a coin battery i don't like
coin batteries they're too dangerous for
kids
but they work like any other battery
right and what this battery is doing is
it's going to light up an led when we
start the simulation
now let's talk about how this works so
we're looking at
um our project here so it's kind of the
middle area is your your board
uh and then over to the right here
you've got all your components that you
can add so you can bring components over
this one started with components so we
don't need to actually bring anything
over
and then over here is just the
information for this tutorial normally
there's nothing over here
and then once you're ready you can click
on start simulation
now start simulation is not that
exciting the only thing that happened is
this
uh led uh lit up right
and the reason it lit up is because
there is a loop
of uh electricity that actually is
flowing through this thing
so the battery has a plus here and so
this is the positive of the battery
it flows through a resistor the resistor
determines how bright the led is
and if you didn't have the resistor it'd
be too bright and it could damage the
led
and then there's an led and led has two
legs they're called the anode and the
cathode
i won't get into the chemistry of it but
but they're called anode and cathode for
chemistry reasons right
and so that that electricity flows
through uh the led
uh down through this black wire and then
back into the battery
and that loop is what makes the led come
on um now of course if there was a piece
missing from that loop like let's say
that wire wasn't there
uh you'd have no no loop uh no light
right
so it stops inflation cool and so the
only thing that this tutorial was trying
to show you
is how the environment works and to run
a simulation
and that's really it for the first
tutorial so i said that there are only
like i think there's four
and one of them is now done right so not
too bad
uh the next tutorial they've got uh is
actually
um is what inspires the uh the project
that we're building today
um it's to build a little traffic light
uh program
so here they're connecting to uh an
arduino uno
an arduino uno is a type of
microcontroller
microcontrollers are in everything like
if you press like a lock in your car
there's some microcontroller that
controls the signal
think of those like little bitty
computers and so we're going to be
programming
this microcontroller which is an arduino
uno to do things
and what we're doing here is we want to
make they'll show you a simulation
we want to make a little red yellow
green traffic light pattern
uh but right now you can see that all of
our leds are blue
and so the goal of this tutorial is
purely
to help you edit the components to
actually change these lights to be the
right colors
that's all they're doing in this but
we'll look at it a little more than that
so let's go ahead and follow the
tutorial and do what it says it says
click on the top led
all right and click on the top led and
then you'll notice that a little box
popped up here
and this little box has information
about this led
the most important thing is that it's
got a color
and we want to switch the top one to be
red now the second one down
if you click on the second one down it
is also
currently blue but as you can guess from
the wire color
uh we want to make it yellow
[Music]
the third one down hopefully you've
picked up the pattern is connected to a
green wire
and it is now green now this
circuit is actually very similar to the
one we saw before with the battery
but it looks more complex it's just that
the arduino here is better than a
battery because the battery is just
always on
whereas the arduino can make something
be on or off
and it fits right but pretend like this
is the battery for a moment
uh current is flowing through this
resistor uh
through this led uh and then to ground
and this ground is just kind of
connected between everybody
yellow is the same way flows through the
yellow and then the ground
and green is the same way and it flows
through here
now all they want you to do on theirs is
to change the color of the lights
and hit start simulation and then it
should go green
yellow red and then it just loops right
so it goes green
yellow red now that's all the tutorial
is going to have you do
uh i just want to glance at one more
thing before we move on
um and so i'm going to click on stop
simulation um and the way that this
whole thing works is via the code
that's on the microcontroller so click
on where it says code here
uh and you can see uh the code that they
wrote for this
you can see it a couple different ways
you can see it as blocks
blocks plus text or text uh what we're
going to do
um and i've done one done want me to
change it um what we're going to do
today is we're going to use
blocks plus text and what we're going to
do the
the two days after this is just straight
text so we're going to be programming
with just straight text
just to glance at it over here we're not
going to memorize it but i'm just going
to see some things it does
an arduino program
has two functions that get called one is
called setup
it does the setup work to prepare things
and then
loop uh this is a function that gets
called over and over again
that keeps going forever in a what's the
word sissy
forever loop yeah and so right now you
can see what they're doing is they're
making
the uh three leds red yellow and green
as output output and output so that's
part of the setup
and then in the loop uh they're doing
different things
uh so here they're making the uh the
green one on
so low low high
and then the yellow one on with a low
high low
and then the red went on with a high low
low
and then there's a little delay here
after each one
to make the simulation so like i said
we're not going to memorize the code
but i just wanted you to have some
appreciation
for how this thing works and the fact
that it's dealing with code
and code is going to be our whole focus
as we're working together
but let's get through the uh the
simulations uh the lessons first
so go ahead and click on next um and it
says that you can
change some things if you want uh but i
think that we'll do that together
so on to the next tutorial the only
thing i don't like about these tutorials
compared to the uh the 3d modeling ones
into the 3d modeling when you got stars
right
the stars went off you got this warm
fuzzy feeling uh where's this there's no
stars
do you miss the stars sissy all right
all right this next one is connecting
wires so a big part of wiring is
connecting wires
and what we're going to do is we're
going to connect two wires to this
circuit
and it shows kind of like a
demonstration of how to connect a wire
and so most of this circuit is all built
it does some crazy things with sound
i'll make sure my sound is cranked up
for this one it's going to be great
but it's missing two important wires the
wires that it's missing is the
connection to the battery
pretty important and so what they want
you to do is they want you to connect
the the red terminal of this nine volt
battery
up to the red line that's up here you'll
notice that if you look at their circuit
there's a red
plus rail and it's actually connected
all the way down
and then there's a red line which makes
it connected to the bottom um
plus rail down here as well uh we'll
talk about breadboards more but the
the rails that are on the outside are
connected all the way down
internally and rails in the middle are
connected all the way across
internally right so to connect a wire
most people they want to click click and
drag and that kind of sort of almost
works
but the best way to do it in tinkercad
circuits is to click once for where you
start
and then i'm no longer touching the
mouse and then to click again
when you get to here and so that
connects the wire
with two clicks is how it works best
now let's talk about colors so wires uh
you can change colors on wires uh the
color
of a wire is completely meaningless
right it's it's just like you spray
painted it red or spray painted blue
it does not matter at all i like to use
colors
to make my code easier to look at so for
example they used a red and a black here
and i just immediately knew hey one of
these is for the the positive
uh from the battery like the plus and
then the other one the black is for the
ground
so that's why colors are nice so we
connected that one
uh and then it says to connect the
ground one uh so this is the same as
what we did before so we click on
the black there and then you do have to
be careful about where it goes to
they want it to go to the black line on
the bottom
and then i choose to change that and
make it be a black wire
now let's try it
uh and if it works it should make a
bunch of noise
uh so mine uh thankfully uh isn't making
a ton of noise
uh because of the how my microphone's
set up uh but yours
uh yours should be making a bunch of
noise
all right sissies yours make a noise yep
okay
[Music]
all right so it makes some uh some
horrible noises
uh when you press the buttons uh so i
just realized i wasn't even pressing the
buttons but
when you press these buttons it should
be like a piano
and each one should make a different
pitch so it's a cute little way to start
learning about
doing some wiring but really we just
connected two
wires in the tutorial uh the next thing
we're going to do is we're going to
learn how to get like
fancier with adding wires and also to
add some components
so this circuit has two double a
batteries so that's about 3 volts total
driving a motor this circuit does work
you can go ahead and test it right now
and what it'll do is it'll spin this
little motor
so these are our pretty inexpensive
motors uh it's
cruising along at some super fast speed
it looks slow here
but it's just because it's going so fast
that it's messing with the frame rate so
it's going super fast right so these
motors has been at like
5902 rpms is what mine is doing right
now
and what they're going to do in this
tutorial is they're going to have you
add
a resistor what's called a photoresistor
instead of that bottom wire so go ahead
and do this click on the bottom wire
uh hit delete and then
in your component scroll until you find
a symbol that kind of looks like that
uh here it is so it's a photo resistor
all right so there's my photo resistor
uh and then what it tells you to do next
is it tells you to rotate it
um to rotate it you hit the r key
so if you hit the r key it'll kind of
rotate it around uh if you rotate it too
much that's fine you can just kind of
keep rotating around or you can hit
shift rotate
shift r to rotate a certain way and get
it to where it's
roughly located about here now what we
want to do is we want to connect the
wire
now uh what we learned before is that
you can click here
and then you can click there and it'll
connect a wire but if you look at their
picture it's got this cool like bend in
it right
um and so how did they get that cool
little bin uh well let me click undo and
let me just try it again
uh so you could click here and then
somewhere down here
and then over here and it puts a cool
bend in it for you right
but even if you don't do it perfect
that's fine you can always grab these
they're called handles
and you can move it around to your
heart's content
you could also change the color to be
red if you'd like
just to practice i'll show you another
way you could have done it let's say
that i had moved it from here to
here and i didn't add that bend well
what i can do is when the wire is
selected i can double click
and add a bend and then i can just move
it to wherever i want so you can always
edit wires
so don't care about if you get them
perfect the next time are you going to
perfect the first time
another thing that's nice to do with
wires is you can change their colors
using hotkeys
and i happen to know that red is the
number two so i just put my wire on here
i'm gonna choose to put it on with no
bend initially and then i'll add a bend
uh after the fact and it was red because
my last wire i
put on was red all right so let's go
ahead and start the simulation uh with
this
so um now um when i start the simulation
you can see it's going much slower
two oh i should have explained this
before rpms
this is revolutions per minute
uh it's a very common unit uh for motors
rpms revolutions per minute so right now
it's going very slow
because of this photocell but what i can
do in this photocell on the show in the
circuit here
is i can change how much light there is
in this photocell
and so if this photocell was in uh the
sun
uh the motor would go very very fast so
like if you took it outside in the sun
i would just start humming away right uh
but if you were in the dark
like inside the house or in a dark room
it'd be slower
and then if you turn off the lights i
would get super slow right
to the point where it's only going at
two rpms
and the reason for that is that this
component called a photo
resistor changes its resistance based on
how much light there is
uh whenever it's dark it's a really high
value
which makes the the circuit have very
little current flow through it
because it's got a lot of resistance uh
does that make sense
but again you can see the path of
current flow goes through here
and that's what makes the loop so the
only thing we wanted to learn about is
adding components so you just drag and
drop them from over here
and then some extra things about adding
wires
[Music]
great so i think that this one is done
uh so that was uh
it for the tutorials uh those are for
some pretty easy tutorials
uh once you've finished the tutorials
there's a button to like go back to the
project page
to be honest where it takes me back to
is not the page i really wanted
uh the page i really wanted i'm gonna
click on the tinkercad logo up here
and this will take me to my dashboard
right so my dashboard has of course the
3d designs
which we made yesterday and then it's
also got the circuits
that we're building today now mine still
has this tutorial here for try circuits
i do not want to click it again i've
already done it once instead what i want
to do is i want to say create
new circuits so this is the way
projects normally work when you click on
create new circuit there's no like
instructions over here
there's just like a blank canvas right
it does tell you that there's a cool
thing called starters
so we'll maybe do that sometime but we
don't really want that
for right now we're just going to click
on show me the basic components and
we'll do some things together
now one thing that's similar to 3d
modeling is when you create a new
project
it will create a crazy name for you up
in the upper left
i'm going to change this one to be
called my led
and what we're going to do is we're just
going to practice adding some components
and wiring them up so here's some
components we're going to add
we're going to add an led so go ahead
and drag an led and drop it onto your
canvas somewhere
and we're gonna add a resistor
um and then we're gonna add a battery so
those are the three things that we saw
before
uh that we use to uh to drive an led
before they used the coin battery this
time i used a double a battery
now what we're going to do is we're
going to before we wire this up we're
going to change
um some of the details of these
components the led can be any color you
want
so you can change the led color if you'd
like so i just
click on it and then i can change the
color of the led
uh the resistor should be a certain size
this is kind of an interesting game but
it can be
some number of kilo ohms that's like
thousands of ohms
right now it's one kilo ohm uh so it's a
thousand ohms
i'm going to switch it to 330 ohms right
so first off right now it's 1k ohm but
if i were to switch it to ohms here
what i did right there was identical
right so i could say one
kilo ohm or 1000 ohms and they're the
same number
i did this though because i actually
want to change it to
330 ohms so
330 ohms is the correct size
for a resistor so that the led is good
and bright but not too bright
and we won't go into the math but 330 is
a good value
next up is the battery so the battery
actually
has some features with them changed to
the first is the count
i actually want four batteries um and
then do you want a built-in switch yes
or no i'm going to say
yes so they actually sell these things
where it's like a little four pack of
double a batteries
uh and then they've got a little like on
off switch on the top here
which is kind of handy in this case four
double a batteries by the way each one
is 1.5 volts uh so four of them together
would be what your wrath feels like
1.4 would be 6 volts
6 volts that's right yep so 6 volts
there all right so let's go ahead
and hook up this circuit now
so to hook up this circuit what i want
to do is i want to take the positive
voltage
uh and connect it to the anode of the
led
uh and then i like to make my wire be
the same color as my led just for fun
and in this case it's already done
because it's green
um and then what i want to do is i want
to take the cathode and connect it to
the resistor
and then take the other end of the
resistor and connect it to
the negative terminal and now what i'm
going to choose to do is i'm going to
make that side be black
because this is the the connection to
ground technically this is the
connection to ground
this is the connection to the led and
this is just some wire in the middle
that can be any color you want right
so this right here is a good
led circuit if you click on start
simulation
when you click on start simulation it
turned your battery pack on for you
which is very nice of them
but you can turn it on and off with this
button here so this is a
properly made led circuit
now what i want you to do just to kind
of practice uh see if you can
practice those skills that we just did
and make a bad led
circuit right next to it so bring over
um another led
i know you could duplicate that one but
bring over another one bring over
another battery pack change the color of
the led
as you see fit set up the battery pack
to have the right features to look just
like that one and this time just for fun
connect it with no resistor so just make
the wire go from the cathode
straight to the negative terminal of the
battery and once you build that
we'll see what happens when you run your
simulation so take a minute and try to
make that happen
all right so i'll go ahead and do it
really quick but hopefully you were
successful in that so i added
an led and then i added just one battery
but then i switch it to four and i
switch it to have a switch that's how i
did that
uh if you try to run the uh the
simulation right now uh your led doesn't
do much because i forgot the wires right
so
make sure you add wires uh and the wires
that i'm gonna add this time i'm gonna
do it wrong i'm gonna add a red one
which i happen to know is color two and
a black one
which i happen to know is color one i
just use the hot keys to save myself
time right
and so now if you start your simulation
uh this is a
bad bad thing right so it says the
current to the led
is 487 milliamps while the
absolute maximum is 20 milliamps right
and so we didn't size our resistor right
and it warns you that this is bad for
leds right
cool so that's all i wanted to do with
this one i just wanted to get you a
little practice
uh adding some things and adding some
wires uh and now we're going to do
something
a lot more complex so my led uh is now
done
uh if you wanted to you could share it
there's different things you could do to
share it
i'm not that worried about it just yet
so go ahead and go back to your
dashboard
the easiest way to get there is to click
on the little tinker logo
and everybody always asks how do i save
uh that led thing it's like well it gets
saved automatically
all right so go ahead and click on new
circuit and we're going to start the
like actual
factual thing we're doing today and that
is to build
the the stop light uh where if i press
this button
uh it'll go through green and then
yellow red so that's our goal today
so our last circuit was just like
batteries and leds and that was all good
but really
what tinkercad simulator is for is it's
for
simulating arduino circuits so the first
thing i want you to do is i want you to
drag an arduino uno r3
out from the side and put it right onto
your canvas
the next thing that i like to do is i
like to rotate it so i like to look at
it this way
it makes the text way easier for my eyes
to read
oh actually you could change the name of
it as well
i'm gonna call it my stoplights you
don't have to start every program uh
with the word my
but you certainly can if you'd like um
in addition to
uh the arduino uno most
people use these breadboards so go ahead
and drag a breadboard
uh from the component area over here
to your workspace and then hit r a
couple times
i usually this is how people kind of set
up their uh their board so they put an
arduino uno right next to the breadboard
uh no shock that's what the good people
at sparkfun did as well right and they
even put a like a little uh backing
piece right so pretty common
uh way to set up things and the reason
breadboards are so popular
is because it's really hard even with
the last circle we did
to hold a bunch of wires i can hold
about two and then i run out of hands
um and so people plug them into these
breadboards and that's a great way to
make connections so now what we're going
to do is we're going to make another led
circuit
so go ahead and take an led i'm going to
put it somewhere near the top
and i'm going to rotate it until it's
sideways
and i'm going to pop it right into the
breadboard
and now this is analogous to physically
like taking an led and putting it in the
breadboard so i really like that
and the way this works is uh whenever i
plug it into the breadboard
i can then plug a wire in anywhere to
this row
and it's like i'm holding it to that leg
of the
of the led so what i want to do is i
want to take this
leg right here and this is the side i
normally put so this is my anode side
this is the one i normally put to a
battery
but i'm going to connect it over to i
think i'll use pin
what the heck i'll use pen four really
you could use about
any pen you wanted on this side 0
through 13. the ones over here are used
for different things they're used for
analog things
but i just want to connect this to pin
4.
if you would like this is a red led
so you could choose to make the wire red
if you want it's completely optional
uh also depending on your level of
ocdness
in your life you can choose to double
click on it
and add bin points and you can make it
um
you know as pretty as you would like um
prettiness
doesn't matter if your wires are a
jumble it still works but you could
choose to make it pretty if you'd like
next we need to add a resistor and now
what i'm going to do with the resistor
is this
i'm going to put it on my breadboard and
so by putting it here
so i very specifically put it in this
exact spot by putting it here
that connects the top of the resistor to
the
cathode of the led and then the bottom
i'm going to connect to this ground rail
that's right here
i like to make my ground rails black
so i'll make it black also again being
very ocd
i'm going to add little bins so that it
kind of looks like it's connected to the
black one
and doesn't like shoot over the top of a
red one again that doesn't really matter
so here's what i'm doing now i've got
power that's going to come from pin four
um an arduino has this ability to kind
of like be like a battery to where it
provides power or not
um and it's gonna go into my anode it's
gonna flow through my led
it's gonna flow through my resistor
which is currently the wrong size
and it's going to flow into this ground
rail uh now there's two things we need
to fix one thing we need to fix is this
ground rail
isn't magic it's not connected to ground
magically you have to actually connect
it to ground somewhere
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to
connect it from right here
to the gnd that's right over here gnd is
short for ground
so my arduino board is going to get
power from the computer
and it's going to be basically my
battery that can be turned on and off
this black wire here by the way it's
connected through this rail
to this wire so it goes to ground there
the other thing i want to fix is i want
a different size resistor instead of one
kiloohm
i'm going to switch it to regular old
ohms
and use 330.
cool so now i have an led circuit
connected to pin 4.
if i start my simulation though you'll
notice that my light does not go on and
off
interestingly there is a light that is
going on and off though uh there's a
little
light right here that's going on and off
that's kind of cool how's that why is
that doing that
um let's go look at the code to figure
out why that's doing that
so click on code so whenever
you um brought over your arduino
it actually had some code for you and
the code that it has is using the blocks
mode
again you can use blocks blocks plus
text
or text today i'm going to primarily use
blocks plus
text the only downside of blocks plus
text is it does take up like most of
your screen
but here's what blocks plus text does
well it lets you use blocks
so this is your tool palette and then
this is your code but it lets you see
the text that gets typed
and this would be a good transition for
tomorrow
when we just go straight into the text
right but the reason that this light is
flashing
is because there's this code that says
set the built-in led
that's this little guy right here to
high
wait for a second and then set it to low
and wait for a second
you can also see that in the text over
here there was a setup function
somebody made pin 13 an output so pin
13 that's this pin right here it
actually is controlling this led
and it's going high wait for a second
low wait for a second
and if you wanted to you could modify it
you can make it be low for for three
seconds and you can see how
change in the blocks uh changes the code
instantly
so that's why it's going high and then
right now it's going low for three
seconds because i just changed that
and then hi and then back off
i don't want to turn that light on
enough though i want to turn this light
over here on and off
so what i'm going to do is i'll tell you
what i'm just going to trash their code
so you can see that this is uh now empty
over here i want to bring in my own code
and what i want to do is i want to set
pin 4
to high and then i want to wait for a
second a wait is over and controlled
so i'm going to wait for a second and
then back into outputs
and then i'm going to set pin 4
to low so you can see that
blocks are nice because there's less
errors that you can make as you're
getting started
but it is also nice to see the code uh
because that'll like
teach you how to how to use uh arduinos
in the wild right
and then after i go low i'm gonna set
this to uh
um wait for one second as well
great uh so now i've got my code here um
so set pin four high wait for a second
set pin for
low wait for a second uh by the way some
people ask
uh you know what's the difference
between this one where it says set pin
blank too high
versus this one set pin this to zero
this one right here is for an analog
right
and you kind of see the the code that's
up over there and that's not what we
want right now we want to set it
all the way higher all the way low so if
you start your simulation now i know
it's crammed way over the corner
uh but you should have this light go on
and off
on off on off
cool not too bad uh let's
build some more uh while i'm building
more i want my code to kind of like hide
to give me more space so i'm just gonna
press that button for code
it'll just kind of hide over there it's
not gone and what i want you to do is i
want you to see if you can build
two more led circuits uh maybe put one
in about the middle put one kind of like
near the bottom but not all the way at
the bottom because i need to leave room
for a button
uh but see if you can make the uh the
middle one be a yellow light
and then make the bottom one be a green
light
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to
not show you how i do it
and i'm going to let you do it on your
own you can optionally make the wires
yellow and greens appropriate but again
remember that doesn't actually matter
so go and pause the video go make it
happen on your own
all right so i've got my beautiful
circuit here um and if i run the
simulation obviously it just does the
red light still
but i'm hoping that i've wired the rest
of these correctly
and now i can write code for them as
well so let's go ahead and
write some code and test to see whether
we've done anything useful
uh or all you know at all so what i want
to do is i'm going to start off by just
making them all
go high oops that was the wrong command
i want to make them all go high together
and then i'll go low together and just
see if that works
so i'm going to grab this set pin
high so my goal is to make them all go
high
uh and then make them all go low so
here's what i'm gonna do
i'm gonna get some commands ready now
i'm gonna set the arguments on them so
i'm gonna make
four three and two
so four three two be high high high
and then i'm gonna make four three two
be low low low
high high high low low low
and now if i start my simulation i can
test to see whether my
wires are correct um and if my wires are
correct
i should see uh flashing uh red yellow
green kind of all together
i'm curious to see how my camper is
doing over here
how's it going sis let's see what hers
looks like
all her wires are in jumble so not
enough no they're not
thought of hey it's working great though
red yellow green
uh which is perfect way to go sis
all right so let's write some more code
uh so let's make it kind of look like
there's a pattern right so let's make it
look like it goes green yellow red
green yellow red uh so you can pause the
video and see if you can do that on your
own
uh but i'll go ahead and show you this
one with you so um right now if we
wanted green
well green would be turning on just
pin two so pin
two it's hard to see everything at once
right pin two is my green one
so if i turn on just pin two so low low
high
and then yellow would be a low
high low uh and then
uh the last one um so i guess i kind of
need another set here sorry
i was sneaky i did a duplicate of the
bottom four lines
um and then the last one is high
low low so high low
so what this should do is this should go
through a little simulation where it's
green
yellow red green yellow
red cool so the last thing i want to do
so i'm almost there
is i want it to only do like green
yellow red
after i push the button so i want to
push the button
and have it go green yellow and then red
and then just stay at red until i push
the button again so we're doing great
so leds are the most common things that
you'll wire up
the next most common thing that you'll
wire up are push buttons
so let's go ahead and stop the
simulation hide the code
let's go ahead and add a push button so
here's a push button
push buttons are sneaky uh they've
actually got four legs
it would appear uh but actually there's
there's only two right
so these two top and bottom that i see
here they're actually connected by a
piece of metal inside
and what you have to do is you have to
put them on your breadboard in a certain
way
and it's not this way because it won't
even spread the middle you've got to
rotate it so i'm going to hit rr
so my push button i brought it over and
i hit rr and now
it should fit right into my breadboard
uh and what's actually happening here is
there's a top to the switch
uh so this top is actually all connected
together by a piece of metal that's
inside
and then there's a bottom to the switch
which is all together
and the way this works is there's
literally a piece of metal in the button
when you press that piece of metal down
it connects the metal on the top and the
metal on the bottom
and it lets it be connected like a wire
and when you're not touching the button
there's no metal connection so it's just
like two wires that are either
touching when you press the button or
not touching and that stops current flow
or allows it so we're going to do is
we're going to connect the bottom to
ground
and then the top i'm going to connect to
pin
0 over here uh and i'm going to make it
blue it's kind of funny instead of using
that i like the hot keys but i can
remember which one blue was so i just
guessed a whole bunch right
all right so we've got a push button uh
that's now connected to
r0 sorry pin 0
and the way this works is internally the
arduino uno is going to pull it
to 5 volts if you don't press the button
but whenever you press the button
it's going to take this blue wire and
it's going to connect it to ground
right so it's kind of interesting that a
push button at least on arduino
is when you press it that makes it low
so a press is a low and then a not press
is a high that's backwards of how some
people think
all right so uh we made a circuit uh
which is
which is how arduinos work and then we
test it with code
so what we want to do is we want to um
check
if somebody presses that button a check
is a
if statement so go to control
find the if statement
and i'll tell you what i'll go ahead and
wrap the if statement around my whole
thing so if you if you move it into just
the right position it wraps it around
the whole thing
now i don't really want the whole thing
in here i just want the
the green and yellow part inside of here
and then this bottom part the red part i
can just take it off right
and in fact this this bottom weight i
don't actually need
so i did a couple changes quickly there
but i think you can see my code to kind
of understand what's going on here so
if you press this button then show me
green
for a second maybe you can make that
like three seconds
uh and then show me yellow for one
second and then go back to just showing
me red
and so the thing we're missing is we're
missing a condition here for our if
you can actually look at our code and
see it's like hey we're kind of missing
a condition right there
for if let's go um we want to see if
that
input is equal to zero so what i'm going
to do is i'm going to go into math
first you'll notice that this is kind of
a triangular like hexagonal looking
shape
i want the one that's a hexagonal
looking shape out of math it's the
second one down
and what i want to do is i want to check
if my input
so i want to read digital pin 0
i want to see if he is equal to
so there's equal to uh i want to see if
he's equal to zero
because zero is a press um and so
if my button is pressed then show me
green
wait for three seconds show me uh yellow
wait for one second and then go back to
red time to try it
uh so if you run your simulation uh what
should happen
is it should just be a solid red led
and then if you press your button so if
i press the button here
uh it goes green uh and then yellow
and then red so that's exactly what this
circuit was doing
when you press the button it goes green
for a little bit
and then after your green cycle is done
it goes yellow and red
and the cool thing about um tinkercad is
it really is just a real circuit
so the way that i program that board
right there is i literally just took my
code right here
uh copied it to my clipboard um and
i opened up a program called the arduino
ide
and i just pasted it inside of here
right so
i think i already had it in here from
what i did earlier i paste it inside of
here
and then i program it to my board i'll
tell you what i want to i want to like
show that that it's really my code i'll
tell you what we'll make the green cycle
be like crazy long we'll use like seven
seconds
on the green cycle so we'll know that
it's actually the latest code
because it'll have that crazy long green
cycle
uh so now this new code is on my board
and so when i press it
it's gonna be green for seven seconds so
i'm gonna guess three
two one switch yeah that's pretty good
uh yellow and then red um so that is uh
what we're building today
um i love uh tinkercad circuits
it is such a good simulator we use it in
college classes right like when we're
teaching microcontrollers
because uh you can do everything in a
virtual environment
and you can learn even if you don't have
any hardware it's great for online
learning like we're doing here
and that is what we're up to today uh so
come back tomorrow
to learn some more about circuits
obviously if you want to play with
circuits just create something and start
start goofing around
we'll try to do some fun things tomorrow
too that i think you'll really enjoy
mckinley did you have fun today did you
get your finished circuit working
nope okay i'll have mckinley pictures
and i'll see you tomorrow
[Music]
bye